moshigames.com 2018-12-30

# Moshi Monsters - Privacy Policy

We're thrilled that you are interested in Moshimonsters.com, where you can adopt your very own pet monster! In this document we'll explain what kinds of questions we'll ask you on our website, and what we do with the information you give us.

Moshi Monsters gives you the ability to have controlled interaction with your friends. We have tried to make this a fun and friendly environment, but the environment on Moshimonsters.com also depends on you. Whenever using this site, or any social networking website, you should be careful about the interactions you have with others.

## Welcome

A big Moshi Monsters welcome to parents, teachers and other concerned adults. Our website, Moshi Monsters.com, is hosted by Mind Candy Ltd., a UK company with offices at 4th Floor Bonhill Building, 15 Bonhill Street, London EC2A 4DN, UK. On this site, with parental permission, kids can participate in a virtual online environment, giving them the opportunity to adopt a virtual pet monster from one of several species, customize it, and bring it to "life". The monster then generates several puzzles each day, and kids who play the games have a chance to earn virtual currency (we call our currency "Rox"). With Rox, kids can "buy" virtual food for their pets and accessories for their pets' rooms. At moshimonsters.com we also provide kids with the ability to have controlled communications, using limited and moderated pinboard text messages with their chosen friends.

In this policy we describe what information we collect, how we collect it, and what we do with it (the policy covers only information collected and used on Moshimonsters.com). Mind Candy strives to comply with both the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, (COPPA) in the U.S. The laws govern the use and collection of information online from kids under 13 (U.S) ans under 16 (EU). To learn more about this law, and about how to protect your kids on interactive online websites, visit http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/edu/pubs/consumer/tech/tec08.shtm for information from the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, and for GDPR here https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/applications/children/.

## What Information We Collect and How We Collect It

### Registration

When users, including children under 16, register and create a monster on Moshimonsters.com, Big Bad Bill Inc. asks them to select a name for their monster, a screen name (also referred to as a monster owner name), and a password; and to provide his or her parent or guardian's email address for children under 16, the child's birth date, gender, and country of residence. Users 16 or older will provide their own email address. In the interactive community features, no additional personally identifying information is required.

In order to use this Web site, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on the registration form, including a user name and password. During registration you are required to give contact information (your parent email address if you are under 16 years of age).

As part of the registration process, we require demographic information (gender, country of residence and birth date); we encourage you to submit this information so we can provide you a more personalized experience. We limit the information we collect, both actively (i.e., what we ask kids) and passively (what we collect through use of web tracking mechanisms like "cookies") to that which is necessary for kids to take part in a particular Moshi Monsters game activity.

Big Bad Bill Inc. is the sole owner of the information collected on Moshimonsters.com. Big Bad Bill Inc. collects personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our Web site including registration and Customer Service contact queries.

To see how we use your information, go to “How Mind Candy Uses the Information it Collects.

### Retention

We only retain web server logs for 30 days.

For Google Analytics, user and event data retention is 26 months, however we do anonymise the ip address and do not send any user personal information

Moshi Owner Accounts will be disabled and anonymised after 2 years of inactivity, but deletion can be requested at any time

### Orders

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on your order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email address, and shipping address) and financial information (such as credit card information and expiration date).

### Agents/Service Providers

Mind Candy, like many other websites, uses Google Analytics to analyze our users to improve the performance and quality of our online services. You can opt-out of analytics using the cookie popup or via our cookie policy page

We use other third parties such as a shipping company to fulfill orders, and a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. We use email and the telephone to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding your order:

We may also engage other third parties to perform services in connection with the operation of our websites. Each of these third parties is contractually obliged to protect the security of any information we share with them, and limited in their use of the information to the services being provided solely to Mind Candy.

  * Amazon (AWS): Website and data storage
  * Crisp Thinking: Crisp provides 100% safe spaces for young users to interact online, keeping them safe from predators, cyberbullies and toxic content. They filter and monitor any text chat if applicable to the service.
  * Internet service provider (ISPs): Your IP address is shared with ISPs to ensure legal or regulatory compliance.
  * Salesforce Desk: Customer service platform

These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for promotional purposes.

### About Cookies

A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We link the information we store in cookies to Personally Identifiable Information (PII) you submit while on our site. Cookies are small text files that we place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. Our cookies themselves do not contain any Personally Identifiable Information (PII). Our cookies reference the PII you provided during registration. We reference the information you provided via an encrypted identifier. Where we link these unique identifiers with your PII, we will treat the unique identifiers as PII as long as they are linked. We use the registration information you provided to contact you if you lose your password or contact you about site updates and changes.

We use both session ID cookies and persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file. <http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie>.

When a Moshi member is using the Moshi Monsters site, Mind Candy collects certain non-personal information by placing and accessing Moshimonsters.com cookies on the user's computer. Cookies do not contain any personal information, so we do not use cookies (or other covert or non-consensual methods) to acquire contact information about the user or other users of the computer.

### Manage Cookies

You can manage your consent of cookies on our websites by clicking on the Cookie Policy link here or on the bottom of our webpages.

Manage cookies:<https://www.moshimonsters.com/eggs/cookie-declaration>.

### Third Party Cookies

The use of cookies by our affiliates and/or service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our affiliates or service providers use session ID cookies to provide demographic and metrics information to Big Bad Bill Inc. and to make it easier for you to navigate our site, in order for you to use the subscription service.

## How Mind Candy Uses the Information it Collects

Mind Candy uses the parent or guardian's email address provided at registration to notify parents that their kids have created a monster and an account on Moshimonsters.com. In that initial notice, parents are provided a link to this privacy policy, and details about how their kids can use Moshimonsters.com. Parents are required to provide their consent before their kid's accounts can be activated. Parent email addresses are used to communicate with parents about their kids in relation to their activity at Moshimonsters.com such as a forgotten password.

Upon activation of an account, the information submitted will be used by Mind Candy to create a personalized monster and will allow the registered user to participate on the Moshimonsters.com website, which contains a variety of interactive community features. Within those features, users are identified in the community by their screen name, age, gender and country of origin. This limited (and non-personal) identifying information, accompanied by a picture of their pet monster, will be displayed to the user or kid's friends and others who have obtained the user or kid's screen name. Monster Owners can make friends only if they know the other Monster Owner's screen name, which they can find in a variety of ways, some examples include knowing the screen name through personal contact offsite, seeing the screen name if the other Monster Owner is mentioned in the Community section of the site (such as if they are the winner of the "Monstar of the Week" competition, "Room of the Week" competition or they may have achieved something newsworthy in-game), or registered Monster Owners seeing screen names that are included in their friend's "friend tree". It is also possible that the Monster Owner could guess a screen name. The recipient must accept the invitation before the two can communicate.

Once an invitation is accepted, the two become online "friends" and can see each other's friends lists, and can use the site to leave moderated messages (for example by posting a message on the friend's "pinboard"). We only allow free-form text in the pin board feature (a brief public, moderated message).

We also use the information that you give to us (including your contact information such as email address) to make our Services the best possible experience for you. For instance, we may use your information to:

  * customise the Services you choose to receive
  * manage your account and your queries
  * improve our Services
  * meet our legal and regulatory obligations and protect our legitimate interests
  * carry out research and analysis, training and quality assurance
  * contact you with important service announcements
  * if you agree, contact you about other Services and products from Mind Candy that we think may be of interest to you
  * if you agree, contact you with advertising from other businesses

If you want to read more about how our site operates, we encourage you to read our Parent's Page.

Please note, we may monitor, record, store and use any telephone call, email or other communication with you internally for training purposes and to improve the quality of our customer service.

### Parental Rights

Parents and legal guardians of kids under 16 ( under 13 in U.S) who are members of Moshimonsters.com have certain rights under COPPA and GDPR, and Mind Candy recognizes those rights. Parents/guardians can consent to collection and use of a kid's personally identifiable information (PII) without consenting to the disclosure of information to third parties. We will not knowingly register children under 16 years old on Moshimonsters.com without parental consent. Without consent, a child under 16 cannot use any of the community features. If a parent does not provide consent, we will delete the information provided during the registration process within a reasonable time period.

A child's participation or access to an activity on our site is not conditioned on their providing more Personal Information than is reasonably necessary for the activity.

Parents/guardians can review information their children have contributed to Moshimonsters.com, request that Mind Candy delete that information, and refuse to allow Mind Candy to collect further information from their kids by contacting our Customer Services department by email at [parents@mindcandy.com](mailto:parents@mindcandy.com). Parents should include their kid's Monster Owner name and the registered (parent's) email address in the email so we can better assist them with their inquiry or request. Mind Candy may ask additional questions or take other steps to verify the identity of parents/guardians before responding to a request to review or delete their kid's information, or a request to refuse further collection from kids.

## Links to Third Party Websites

We provide links to third party websites. Before a Monster Owner can exit our website, we explain that the Monster Owner is leaving our website, and going to the website of a third party. Once they leave our site, he or she may submit information to a third party, over whom we have no authority or control, and who may have different information collection and use practices. Users and Parents/guardians should always read a company's privacy policy carefully, including those companies to whom we provide links, before submitting information to them.

## Information Sharing and Disclosure

Mind Candy does not share, rent or trade personally identifying information about our registered users, including kids under 16, with non-affiliated third parties (i.e., companies who are not one of our corporate affiliates or who are not providing support to the internal operations of our company) for their promotional purposes. Mind Candy makes every reasonable effort to disallow and discourage users and kids from sharing personally identifying information with each other via the community features via a filter system and live moderators. The only information that can be openly shared in the Moshimonsters.com community features are screen names (and kids are cautioned not to select their real names), country of residence, age, gender and moderated messages. Users and kids who use the pin board features do have the opportunity to draft their own messages to their friends, but we do not prompt any site users to provide any identifying information about themselves.

Mind Candy may share other information submitted on its site - non-personal information - to provide requested products or services, if permission is granted, or under the following circumstances:

  * We share personal information in certain cases in order to prevent, take action against or investigate situations regarding illegal activities, fraud or suspected fraud, events in which threats or potential threats to the physical safety of any person or persons is evident, when violations of Mind Candy's terms of use occur, or in other situations required by law.
  * We respond to subpoenas, court orders and other legal processes, or make use of information in exercising our legal rights or establishing defense against legal claims.
  * We transfer information about users if Mind Candy is acquired by or merged with another company. In this event, Mind Candy notifies the user in advance of any information transfer and before it may become subject to any other privacy policy.

We reserve the right to disclose your personally identifiable information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our Web site.

## Community Disclosures

If you use the blog on this Web site to make comments, you should be aware that any personally identifiable information you submit there can be read, collected, or used by other users of the blog, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. Though we pre-moderate the blog comments, we are not responsible for the personally identifiable information you choose to submit in this site.

## Opting Out

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or you may communicate by emailing us at [helpme@moshimonsters.com](mailto:helpme@moshimonsters.com) please type UNSUBSCRIBE in the subject line, or you may contact us in writing by posting your mail to: Mind Candy Ltd, 4th Floor Bonhill Building, 15 Bonhill Street, London EC2A 4DN, UK, to opt-out.

## Updating/Accessing/Amending/Correcting Personally Identifiable Information

If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, amend, delete/remove or deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at [helpme@moshimonsters.com](mailto:helpme@moshimonsters.com) or by contacting us by postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request to change the information within 3 days and action any deletion within 30 days.

## Confidentiality and Security

Information a user or child submits to Moshimonsters.com that relates to his or her account is password-protected. No employee of Mind Candy nor any automated system will contact a user or parent by email or using the MonsterMail or messaging systems asking for a user or child’s login details, password or any other personal information related or unrelated to a Mind Candy service or product. If any message claiming or appearing to come from Mind Candy or any of its related websites is sent to you asking for such information, please report it immediately to [helpme@moshimonsters.com](mailto:helpme@moshimonsters.com).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personally identifiable information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can send email us at [helpme@moshimonsters.com](mailto:helpme@moshimonsters.com).

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Caring for a monster is a challenging process, and in order to ensure the monsters are looked after properly and their owners kept stimulated, the practices of Moshimonsters.com may alter from time to time. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it.

If we make material changes to how we collect and use Personal Information from children under age 16, we will notify parents by email in order to obtain verifiable parental consent for the new uses of the child's Personal Information.

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page.

## Questions and Suggestions

If you have questions or suggestions, please email us at [info@moshimonsters.com](mailto:info@moshimonsters.com) or mail us at: attn: Customer Service, Mind Candy, 4th Floor Bonhill Building, 15 Bonhill Street, London EC2A 4DN, UK.

Effective Date: 22/05/18
